IAN FLETCHER

St. Louis, MO 63130

Phone: 3146100329 | Email: <u>ianfletcher314@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/ian-fletcher-a51420124/</u>

GitHub: https://github.com/ianfletcher314
Portfolio: https://ianfletcher314.github.io/portfolio/

Full Stack Developer and Customer Service Specialist with experience in sales, music technology, and distribution management. Productive at the intersection of web development and customer interaction. Able to work productively individually or on a team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Node Js | English, Portuguese, French

Technologies: React, Express, MongoDb, jQuerry, AJAX, MySQL, Cryptr, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Brasilia

https://github.com/ianfletcher314/brazilianrestaurant https://ianfletcher314.github.io/brazilianrestaurant/

- Restaurant application for mid to small sized Brasilian restaurant in St. Louis
- Responsive landing site that directs users to three menus and GrubHub
- HTML / CSS / JSX / React / Bootstrap /∆rtgrid

Happy Health

https://github.com/ianfletcher314/happyhealth | https://happyhealth404.herokuapp.com/

- Cloud-based application that gives the user multiple meal options based on the amount of calories the user wants to consume
- Designed user creation and authentication components, facilitated the connection of the front and back ends, hid development credentials and deployment
- MongoDb, Express, React, Node Js, Bcrypt, Material UI, Connect-Mongo, Dotenv

KisKis

https://github.com/ianfletcher314/kiskis | https://lit-escarpment-01189.herokuapp.com

- Security application to encrypt and store sensitive information the user inputs securely. The user can decrypt and view their information after logging in with a unique username and password
- Project management and Github maintenance, worked on a team designing the front end of the website, organized and refactored code
- Node Js, Express-Handlebars, MySql, Cryptr, Materialize, CSS

EXPERIENCE

Character Designer and Play Tester First Level Games LLC

2020 – 2021 St. Louis, MO

Design characters, storylines, and factions for FLG's virtual card game. Collaborate with a diverse team of writers and game developers to create the game's fictional world.

• Cultural consultant for the South American region

• Lead the creation of one of the 5 main factions in the game

Store Lead 2019–2020 Guitar Center St. Louis, MO

Floor Manager facilitating the sales of pro audio gear, live sound gear, guitars, and other products. Aids in the maintenance and appraisal of live sound gear.

• Oversaw 250K in sales during 6 months as sales associate

 Promoted to Store Lead and tasked with managing customer interactions and onboarding new associates

Sound Engineer Mr.F Production 2015-2021

St. Louis, MO

Wrote, recorded, arranged, mixed, and mastered music to help bring a client's sonic vision to life.

Produced music for Bustle and Abercrombie & Fitch Commercial

Client Services Planet Fitness 2018-2019

New York, NY

Assisted members with account management, scheduling appointments, and financial inquiries.

- Managed tours of the 3 floor facility for potential members
- Aided in the training and on-boarding of new Client Service Representatives

Customer Service Manager True Gault

2016-2017

St. Louis, MO

Managed communications on behalf of the company, including all customer service inquiries. Organized and operated product showroom and supervised inventory, both in the office and at off-site storage unit

- Project managed the company's customer service transition from Gmail to ZenDesk
- Scheduled client meetings and oversaw company recruitment
- Conducted extensive company research on everything from venture capitalist profiles to potential office locations

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: Washington University, University City, MO A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

Bachelors in the Arts: New York University, New York, NY Concentration: Power Structures Within Media Industries